that both no re
No
one your and launch
the SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket as nasa terms
to the private sector
resupply
space
of a future where space bring
civilization
is a far more exciting and inspiring
future than one where we are not
capture is comprised
thank you say shit looks like we've got
us a dragon by the tail.
a long-term goals is to be able to
develop technology to transport millions
of people to mars
which will preserve the peace for
Humanity events for calamity
on on earth 0
absolutely think we would have a future
where humanity is
out there is falling stars and where we
have human civilization on mobile
planets
when the US government decided
stop funding the fe3+ cofounder case
Holland have fun motor
you on my stepped up to the plate he
invested $100 million dollars these own
money into faiths act
I was able to sit down with you on it
headquarters in southern california
to talk about how he's making space
explorations hot
of for the next generation the big
breakthrough that would have officially
the SpaceX
is to breed fully erect the reusable
rocket the reason that's so important
is that the the cost is the film the
option of is very low it's actually
about
.3 percent because the Rockets for up to
60 miles off the coast about
about talent is only about two hundred
thousand dollars if we're able to reuse
the Rockets pic be a dramatic
reduction in the cost thereof
spaceflight in one
fire you that well as a kid I I I
thought about
what would most affect the future of
humanity and I and I think
have faced it's fair to say in public
pretty obvious
most that a a future where space bring
civilizations
is a far more exciting inspiring future
than one worry of on Oct
even though in their follow 50 when I
was that has forced the finale
has both people went to the moon in
effect we always there
vicariously quality here
go as planned but fly in space
exploration for and you
can we be focusing on what's going on
here a largely agreed that
we should have a you ninety nine percent
plus
up our energy focus on solving problems
on earth
I'm but I think we need to a preserve a
small about
for a future beyond a you can say well
how much money should we spend
on on extended benefit face
there and so they should be far less
than we spent on health care
but maybe more than we spent on lipstick
I'm
and I I like we thank you to
nah known off from that attack benefits
they're just saying
I'm that you know we should probably
somewhere between those two numbers and
and them penny therefore it quits for
towards lower its actually enters
expenses
so you said that you your goal is to
eventually take
million parts multi-millions yeah going
to be
fun however will not support that is the
key threshold
I think I'm is is half-million dollars
to move some of
wife at in order to achieve that you
have to first we'll have a fully
reusable system
that's 12 months back a hotfix the
rights
up for health combination I think with
with methane
a fifth in Austin you can do it if
someone were to
work hard save money and really have
that as their goal
that by the time they fade if they're
sorta amid mid-flight for you
most people in america good could do
that if they let their guard saving up
yes and then of course you sell your
house to any and all your belongings on
earth does
you're moving flies it's not this I mean
I still have my dog for a case that is
would be crazy fit your numbers there
you sell your cell you can either
you help half an hour for you have a
free returns think about whether a tenth
3 the spacecraft faxer I okay you
lot of times actually people one walk
upon bike so far more success is not one
possible outcome
I'm this case I think success has won
the possible outcomes that doesn't mean
we will achieve it but
I've carpet at the point that if
possible while half a million dollars
sounds expensive
remember that the russians once offer
trips for $35 million dollars just to go
to the space station
well creating a civilization on mars
found a little tough it's certainly not
going to stop you on my
from achieving his dream one day
colonizing the red planet what advice do
you have for young people
work training and history I do think
more people should study in Syrian
science and
actually I say particularly engineering
because engineering is the
oppose this thing to magic that exists
in the real world engineering is
creating some new
device or that that never existed before
and neck back to do things today the
that would be considered magic hundreds
of years ago it's pretty amazing what's
a
what what do we can create images and
your holograms things like that and and
all these things would have
got your burned at the stake I'm you
for years ago when is the next call
crash what nextag.com free and
what industry should they be now well
I think and their opportunities in
energy sustainable energy
and artificial intelligence
and
and genetics as a polio-free
the three big areas and what advice do
you have for young people who are trying
to get their startups of
I think the that the thing to do is to
try to create
a demonstration article everything works
on PowerPoint but
if you actually have the physical item
for the software you know some
demonstration software
that that's much more convincing people
that a powerful presentation or or any
business plan give an internship program
here can you tell me a little bit about
fat yes we we we hire
actually quite a few interns the here's
a couple hundred a year
a record you're looking for evidence for
exceptional abilities so
I you have somebody competed in like a
design will fly competition
or a Formula SAE racing wanna States
science fair where they do that sorta as
evidence a
exceptional voted in one form or another
GPS is one
one element actors but slightly higher
weighting on
having one some sort of competition so
someone for me before this interview
that you work you
well I'm a test yeah why did you decide
to do that
well I think it's important to maximize
vacation much more sativa
the serve that the Spartans to afford
I'm
so I i care about. effective execution
at the company and the more you insulate
yourself from
information for all be back in the
company the worse
decisions he made this is the third
successful venture for you on my
he's got degrees in both physics and
business
and he promotes sciences the pathway to
success for the next generation
how does a recession back to companies
like SpaceX have you often
back the recession we've actually done
recent reasonably well actually
and in California yeah yeah their work
we've done fairly well
I will continue to grow ok throughout
the recession
and that really really hasn't had a
negative effect on SpaceX
we might have grown slightly faster but
we grew very fast
and I do better with such basics it's
like Valley
or some california and the end I said to
use that some help with mister
a larger bases aerospace engineering
talent in Southern California
but then with has the a test actually
this
but more in in in Northern California
because
electric cars you think about the
problems with the associated with that
it sort of software engineering
electrical engineering its its batteries
skills that are actually better
in Northern California California's
state needs to be cautious about
I'm the level of taxation and regulation
that better price
yeah I'm surprised that your base here
well
you know when I started pick two
companies
the California max that at the Marshall
factor in california is 9 percent I
think it's now
almost 14 percent that's a fifty percent
increase
success of the company's and its me it
makes a progressively harder to to hire
people
I'm and two to compensate them had a
lovely
if we're competing against companies
that are in states that have
02 low personal tax or in countries that
arm
a much cheaper to operate in it's
fortunate that California's is
is a great place to live help we must be
careful not to two over regulate
companies
in in the state make difficult to
operate so you know
your technology why is that why did you
make that
well at SpaceX we don't and at times
that we do
I'm would have gotten anything that hard
to
to determine just by looking at the
Rockets gonna send the
technology just by looking at the rocket
them then we will sometimes
issue a patent what we want pat is
anything that's hidden or hard to
determine
about technology russia today in China
long-term our toughest competitors I
think we would have some
some challenge enforcing a patent suit
against the Chinese or Russian
government so up until recently when
people think I'm space exploration they
think that that is the role of the
federal government
for do you think your business your
company is just asking who are perhaps
more capable of well
I think I think that that the likely
solution is going to be some combination
over a private and and government
efforts are not completely private
no I don't think it's like to become
fully privatized ok but I do think it's
likely to be majority
private and coming to be quite helpful
in in the beginning
while I'm in a very much for proponents
have a free market
there's limited role for government in
certain certain areas
particularly where two large expenditure
but it provides a small amount so good
for the whole
the whole country something like that
the hubble space telescope is a good
example
I'm you know what we learnt a great deal
about about universe we got these
incredible
images and they're just so the stunning
images I think it really
it was helpful and inspiring kids to
study engineering and science like
anything
to learn more about that and life has to
be about more than just solving problems
it can't be
that all you all you do is wake up and
just for
solve one was for power know they have
to be exciting inspiring events that
make life worth living in the first
place
against all odds you on moscow is
inspiring a new generation of explorers
and innovators
who believe that space travel is
possible for everyday people
not in some faraway time but in the very
near future
for next-generation TV i'm michelle feel
could be